Register of the Frank A. Golder papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank Alfred Golder papers
1861-1929
XX058
Hoover Institution Archives
38 manuscript boxes, 12 envelopes (16.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, diaries, memoranda, transcripts of documents from Russian archives, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian history in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, the Russian American Company in Alaska, conditions in Russia during the Russian Revolution and Civil War, and American Relief Administration work in Russia.
Golder, Frank Alfred, 1877-1929
Access
Boxes 1-38 closed. Microfilm use copy available. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (46 reels).
Biographical Note
1877, August 11 Born, Odessa, Russia
1880 Arrived in the United States
1898 Ph.B., Bucknell University
1900-1902 Teacher in U.S. public schools in Alaska the Aleutian Islands
1903 M.A., Harvard University
1904-1908 Studied in Berlin, Paris and St. Petersburg
1908-1909 Instructor in history, University of Missouri
1909 Ph.D., Harvard University Instructor in history and economics, Boston University
1910 Instructor of history, University of Chicago
1910-1914 Assistant professor of history, Washington State College
1914 Author, Russian Expansion on the Pacific
1915-1920 Professor of history, Washington State College
1917 Author, Guide To Materials for American History in Russian Archives Conducted research in Russian archives for Carnegie Institute and American Geographical Society
1917-1919 Member, Colonel House Commission of Inquiry
1918 Author, The Russian Revolution
1920-1923 Member, American Relief Administration
1921-1929 Associate Professor and Professor of history, Stanford University
1922 Author, Bering's Voyages
1925 Author, History of Russia
1927 Author, Documents of Russian History, On the Trail of the Russian Famine and Paul Jones in Russia
1928 Author, March of the Mormon Battalion
1929 Died, Stanford, California
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, writings, diaries, memoranda, transcripts of documents from Russian archives, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian history in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, the Russian American Company in Alaska, conditions in Russia during the Russian Revolution and Civil War, and American Relief Administration work in Russia.
American Relief Administration.; Rossiisko-amerikanskaia kompaniia.; Alaska--Description and travel; International relief.; Prisoners of war.; Russia--History--Nicholas II, 1894-1917.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; World War, 1914-1918--Prisoners and prisons.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Other Finding Aids note
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Biographical File, 1914-1929
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, certificates, clippings, appointment books, bibliographies, printed matter, relating to the career and life of F. Golder. Arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General (Reel 1)
    Box/Folder 1: 1-2
  - Address book
    Box/Folder 1: 3
  - Bibliographies
    Box/Folder 1: 4
  - Certificates
    Box/Folder 1: 5
  - Clipping, "Dr. Golder in Finland, 1920," Helsingin Sanomat, November 12, 1920
    Box/Folder 1: 6
  - Golder Memorial Fund file
    Box/Folder 1: 7-9
  - Identification cards
    Box/Folder 1: 10
  - Letters of recommendation
    Box/Folder 1: 11
  - Obituaries
    Box/Folder 1: 12-14
  - Passports, visas (Reel 2)
    Box/Folder 1: 15
  - Teaching material, Stanford University, History 14, introductory seminar, August 1925
    Box/Folder 1: 16
- Diaries, 1914-1927
  Handwritten and typewritten diaries arranged chronologically.
  - 1914-1922
    Box/Folder 2: 1-5
  - 1920-1921
    Box/Folder 2: 6
  - 1921-1922 (Reel 3)
    Box/Folder 2: 7
  - 1921-1922
    Box/Folder 3: 1-6
  - 1922
    Box/Folder 3: 7
  - 1922 (Reel 4)
    Box/Folder 4: 1
  - 1925-1926
    Box/Folder 4: 2
  - 1925-1927
    Box/Folder 4: 3
- Speeches and Writings, 1914-1928
  Handwritten, typewritten, and printed copies of speeches and writings by F. Golder with related correspondence, notes and research materials. Arranged chronologically by title.
  - General
    - Unidentified drafts and notes
      Box/Folder 4: 4-5
    - Untitled fragments and writings
      - Alaska
        - General
          Box/Folder 4: 6-7
        - Boundaries, 19th century
          Box/Folder 4: 8
        - History, 18th and 19th centuries
          Box/Folder 4: 9
        - Russians in, 18th and 19th centuries (Reel 5)
          Box/Folder 4: 10
        - Social customs, 18th and 19th centuries
          Box/Folder 5: 1
      - Bering's expeditions
        Box/Folder 5: 2
      - California, Spanish settlers, 19th century
        Box/Folder 5: 3
      - Cartography, North Pacific Ocean
        Box/Folder 5: 4
  - "Across Arizona's Desert on Horseback,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 5. Holograph and typescript
  - "The Baltic Provinces,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 6. Typescript
  - "A Day With the Mormons,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 7. Typescript
  - "The Development of Russian Painting,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 8. Typescript
  - "Father Herman of Alaska,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 9. Holograph
  - "Investigation of the Food Situation in the Ruhr,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 10. Typescript
  - "A Little Journey Into the Land of the Monks."
    Box/Folder 5: 11. Printed copy
  - "Keeping Faith With God,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 12. Printed copy
  - "O'Hara,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 13. Printed copy
  - "Pete Nelson,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 14. Typescript
  - "Proposals for Russian Occupation of the Hawaiian Islands,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 15. Typescript
  - "Ross, California,", undated (Reel 6)
    Box/Folder 5: 16. Holograph
  - "Russia,", undated
    box/Folder 5: 17. Typescript
  - "Russia and Japan, Kuropatkin,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 18. Holograph
  - Russian bibliography, undated
    Box/Folder 5: 19. Typescript
  - "The Russian University Professor,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 20. Typescript
  - "Russo-Japanese Entente - Recent Events and Present Policies in China,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 21. Holograph
  - "A Survey of the Ukrainian Situation,", undated
    Box/Folder 5: 22. Typescript
  - "Tales From Kodiak Island," The Journal of American Folk-Lore, undated
    Box/Folder 5: 23. Printed copy
  - "The Songs and Stories of the Aleuts With Translations From Veniaminov," The Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1907 April/June
    Box/Folder 5: 24. Printed copy
  - "Eskimo and Aleut Stories From Alaska," The Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1909 January/March
    Box/Folder 5: 25. Printed copy
  - "Primitive Warfare Among the Natives of Western Alaska," The Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1909 July/September
    Box/Folder 5: 26. Printed copy
  - "A Survey of Alaska," Washington Historical Quarterly, 1913 April
    Box/Folder 5: 27. Printed copy
  - Russian Expansion on the Pacific, Cleveland, 1914
    Box/Folder 6: 1. Typescript
  - "Letter of Kamehameha II to Alexander I, 1820," The American Historical Review, 1915 July
    Box/Folder 6: 2. Printed copy
  - "The Russian Fleet and the Civil War," The American Historical Review, 1915 July
    Box/Folder 6: 3. Printed copy
  - "Catherine II and the American Revolution," American Historical Review, 1915 October
    Box/Folder 6: 4. Typescripts and printed copies
  - "Mining in Alaska Before 1867," The Washington Historical Quarterly, 1916 July
    Box/Folder 6: 5. Printed copy
  - "The Russian Offer of Mediation in the War of 1812," Political Science Quarterly, 1916 September
    Box/Folder 6: 6. Research notes and printed copy
  - "The Attitude of the Russian Government Toward Alaska,", 1917
    Box/Folder 6: 7. Printed copy
  - "Ukraine,", 1918 February 15
    Box/Folder 6: 8. Typescript
  - "The Russian Revolution," The University Magazine, April 1918
    Box/Folder 6: 9. Printed copy
  - "The Don Province,", 1918 April 2
    - Research material
      Box/Folder 6: 10
    - Typescript
      Box/Folder 6: 11
  - "Lithuanian Political Parties in America,", 1918 April 12 (Reel 7)
    Box/Folder 7: 1. Typescript
  - "Siberia,", 1918 May 25
    Box/Folder 7: 2. Typescript
  - "Lithuania,", 1918 August 20
    - Drafts and notes
      Box/Folder 7: 3
    - Typescript
      Box/Folder 7: 4
  - "Ukraine,", 1918 November 1
    - Drafts, notes, research materials
      Box/Folder 7: 5-6
    - Typescript
      Box/Folder 7: 7
  - "England,", 1920 (Reel 8)
    Box/Folder 7: 8. Typescript
  - "The Purchase of Alaska," American Historical Review, 1920 April
    Box/Folder 7: 9. Printed copy
  - "The American Civil War Through the Eyes of a Russian Diplomat," American Historical Review, 1921 April
    Box/Folder 7: 10. Printed copy
  - "The Church Situation,", 1923 December 21
    Box/Folder 7: 11. Typescript
  - "Aim in Life or Career in Life," speech, Burlingame, California, 1924 June 20
    Box/Folder 8: 1. Typescript
  - Excerpt from a letter by F. Golder, Paris, relating to Russian emigres, 1924 November 6
    Box/Folder 8: 2. Typescript
  - "Russian-American Relations During the Crimean War," American Historical Review, 1926 April
    Box/Folder 8: 3. Printed copy
  - Documents of Russian History, 1914-1917, 1927
    Box/Folder 8: 4-5. Drafts and notes
  - "F. A. Golder (Autobiography),", 1927
    Box/Folder 8: 6. Typescript
  - On the Trail of the Russian Famine, 1927
    - Contract with Stanford University Press, undated
      Box/Folder 8: 7
    - Correspondence, 1923-1927
      Box/Folder 8: 8
    - Drafts and notes
      Box/Folder 8: 9-10
    - Typescript (Reel 9)
      Box/Folder 8: 11
  - "Ivanovna - Christmas Story for 1928,"
    Box/Folder 9: 1. Typescript
  - March of the Mormon Battalion, typescript, 1928
    Box/Folder 9: 2-4
  - March of the Mormon Battalion, typescript (cont.), 1928 (Reel 10)
    Box/Folder 9: 5-7 and 10: 1-2
  - "Proposals for Russian Occupation of the Hawaiian Islands," The Hawaiian Islands, 1930
    Box/Folder 10: 3
- Correspondence, 1902-1929
  Letters, reports, memoranda, printed material and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1917-1926 (Reel 11)
    Box/Folder 10: 4-5
  - General, 1917-1926 (Reel 12)
    Box/Folder 11: 1-3
  - Adams, Ephraim D.
    - 1920
      Box/Folder 11: 4
    - 1921
      Box/Folder 11: 5-6
    - 1922 (Reel 13)
      Box/Folder 11: 7
    - 1923
      Box/Folder 11: 8
  - Adams, William, 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 1
  - Adriianova, Anna, 1923-1925
    Box/Folder 12: 2
  - Alexandine, Olga, 1923-1924
    Box/Folder 12: 3
  - American Chamber of Commerce for the Levant, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 3A
  - American Red Cross Commission, Riga, 1920
    Box/Folder 12: 4
  - American University of Beirut, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 5
  - Arnheim, Captain, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 6
  - Baker, William, undated
    Box/Folder 12: 7
  - Baltic, V., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 8
  - Beach, W. G., 1928
    Box/Folder 12: 9
  - Beer, Mr., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 10
  - Beneshevitch, Vladimir, 1923
    Box/Folder 12: 11
  - Benko, Arthur, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 12
  - Benningsen, George, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 13
  - Benoit, Alexandre, 1926
    Box/Folder 12: 14
  - Bertling, Dr., 1920
    Box/Folder 12: 15
  - Bollenbeck, J. W., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 16
  - Bowden, C. G., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 17
  - Brewster, W. M., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 18
  - Brigham, William Y., 1915
    Box/Folder 12: 19
  - Bristol, Mark S., 1923
    Box/Folder 12: 20
  - Bruiningk, Lucie von, 1926-1927
    Box/Folder 12: 21
  - Burns, E. I., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 22
  - Chace, Olive, 1928
    Box/Folder 12: 23
  - Cherniashin, N. and Stepanov, Ivan, 1923
    Box/Folder 12: 24
  - Childs, J. Rives, 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 25
  - Chopey, Nicholas, 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 26
  - Coolidge, Archibald C., 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 27
  - Coombs, J. P., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 28
  - Cox's Shipping Co., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 29
  - Croly, H., 1917
    Box/Folder 12: 30
  - Delegation Armenienne a la Conference de la Paix, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 31
  - Donskey, Helen, 1922-1923
    Box/Folder 12: 32
  - Ek, Victor, 1920
    Box/Folder 12: 33
  - Eliot, Henrietta
    - 1917
      Box/Folder 12: 34
    - 1920-1923
      Box/Folder 12: 35
    - 1925, 1958
      Box/Folder 12: 36
  - Eliot, Thomas, 1917-1919, 1928-1929
    Box/Folder 12: 37
  - Fisher, Edgar J., 1921-1924
    Box/Folder 12: 38
  - Franklin, E. C., 1926-1927
    Box/Folder 12: 39
  - Galpin, Perrin E., 1925-1927
    Box/Folder 12: 40
  - Gates, C. F., 1923 (Reel 14)
    Box/Folder 12: 41
  - Gay, H. Nelson, 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 42
  - Georgia. Legation (France), 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 43
  - Golovin, Nikolai N., 1920
    Box/Folder 12: 44
  - Goodrich, James P., 1922-1927
    Box/Folder 12: 45
  - Gregg, John P., 1927
    Box/Folder 12: 46
  - Hangan, Mr., 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 47
  - Harlow, S. Ralph, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 48
  - Heinrichs, Erik, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 49
  - Henderson, W. L., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 50
  - Herter, Christian, 1922-1923
    Box/Folder 12: 51
  - Hertz, Friedrich, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 52
  - Heyking, Alphonse, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 53
  - Hirscht, Albert, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 54
  - Hoover, Herbert C., 1924-1927
    Box/Folder 12: 55
  - Hossfeld, Henry, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 56
  - Hungary. Prime Minister, 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 57
  - Huntington, George H., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 58
  - Igelstrom, V., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 59-60
  - Jackson, 1917
    Box/Folder 12: 61
  - Jensen, Marie, 1902
    Box/Folder 12: 62
  - Jonescu, A. S., 1922
    Box/Folder 12: 63
  - Jordan, David Starr, 1923
    Box/Folder 12: 64
  - Judd, Albert F., 1915
    Box/Folder 12: 65
  - Karpovich, M. M., 1918
    Box/Folder 12: 66
  - Kingston, H. L., 1921
    Box/Folder 12: 67
  - Lopp, W. T., 1924-1927
    Box/Folder 13: 1
  - Lucca, Barbara, 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 2
  - Lutz, Ralph
    - 1920
      Box/Folder 13: 3
    - 1921
      Box/Folder 13: 4
    - 1922
      Box/Folder 13: 5
    - 1923
      Box/Folder 13: 6
  - Maklakov, Vasilii, 1923
    Box/Folder 13: 7
  - Mares, Frant, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 8
  - Marez, M. G. Des, 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 9
  - Mezerole, W. H., 1926-1928
    Box/Folder 13: 10
  - Mez, John, 1924
    Box/Folder 13: 11
  - Miliukov, Paul, 1920-1921
    Box/Folder 13: 12
  - Murison, Elizabeth L., 1915
    Box/Folder 13: 13
  - Murphy, Matthew, 1926 (Reel 15)
    Box/Folder 13: 14
  - Near East Relief, 1921-1922
    Box/Folder 13: 15
  - Oettingen, E. von, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 16
  - Paillon, Arthur, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 17
  - Peet, W. W., 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 18
  - Peresvet (Murav'ev, V.)., 1923
    Box/Folder 13: 19
  - Petri, Paul, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 20
  - Pettay, J., 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 21
  - Poillon, Arthur, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 22
  - Poopu, Colonel, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 23
  - Pribram, A. F., 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 24
  - Putnam, Herbert, 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 25
  - Reconstruction (Vienna), 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 26
  - Rickard, Edgar, 1924-1927
    Box/Folder 13: 27
  - Ringland, Arthur C., 1922, 1925
    Box/Folder 13: 28
  - Robins, Margaret D., 1917
    Box/Folder 13: 29
  - Robins, Raymond, 1917
    Box/Folder 13: 30
  - Romanian Academy, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 31
  - Royal Academy of Sciences, Belgrade, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 32
  - Russian Trade Delegation to the United States, 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 33
  - Ryan, A. C., 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 34
  - Sergii, Archbishop of Finland and Vyborg (petition to visit Valaam Monastery, Lake Ladoga), 1914
    Box/Folder 13: 35
  - Shakhovskoi, Dimitrii, 1915, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 36
  - Shipkoff and Co., 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 37
  - Smetona, A., 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 38
  - Sokoloff, Boris, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 39
  - Sokolov, N. D., 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 40
  - Steiner, J., 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 41
  - Stone, David, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 42
  - Strawn, Silas H., 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 43
  - Sukhanov, Nikolai, 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 44
  - Sussdorff, Louis, 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 45
  - Szlupas, J., 1918
    Box/Folder 13: 46
  - Tobien, Alexander, 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 47
  - Topelius, Guy, 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 48
  - Tukalevskii, V. N., 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 49
  - United States. Legation (Switzerland), 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 50
  - University of Helsingfors Library, 1920
    Box/Folder 13: 51
  - Urbanavycius, C., 1918
    Box/Folder 13: 52
  - Wahren, Ivar, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 53
  - Waldenfels, Otto, 1921
    Box/Folder 13: 54
  - Westergaard, Waldemar, 1922
    Box/Folder 13: 55
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1917-1927
    Box/Folder 13: 56
  - Miscellaneous
    Box/Folder 13: 57-58
- Imperial Russian and Soviet Archives, 1904-1923
  Handwritten and typewritten transcriptions, by F. Golder, of archival materials for the period before, during and after the Russian Revolution, from various repositories. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    Box/Folder 14: 1
  - General (Reel 16)
    Box/Folder 14: 2
  - Alaska, Sale of, 1867-1868
    Box/Folder 14: 3
  - Catherine II, Empress of Russia, 1729-1796
    Box/Folder 14: 4
  - Franco-Japanese Treaty, 1907
    Box/Folder 14: 5
  - Iuzhno-Zemel'nyi Bank
    Box/Folder 14: 6
  - Kamchatka
    Box/Folder 14: 7
  - Moscow and the West (Reel 17)
    Box/Folder 14: 8
  - Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1868-1918
    - Abdication, 1917 March 2
      Box/Folder 14: 9
    - Stolypin, Petr A., correspondence, 1906-1911
      Box/Folder 14: 10
  - Romanov, House of, Rules for succession
    Box/Folder 15: 1
  - Rurik genealogy, 1908
    Box/Folder 15: 2
  - Russia
    - Black Sea ports, 19th century
      Box/Folder 15: 3
    - Commerce - United States
      - General
        - 1820s
          Box/Folder 15: 4
        - 1878
          Box/Folder 15: 5
        - 1889
          Box/Folder 15: 6
      - Columbia River, Occupation of, 1821
        Box/Folder 15: 7
    - Diplomatic correspondence
      - General, 1807-1808 (Reel 18)
        Box/Folder 15: 8
      - Letter of N. G. Garting to to A. S. Suvorin, 1904 May
        Box/Folder 15: 9
    - Foreign policy
      - Undated
        Box/Folder 15: 10
      - 19th century
        Box/Folder 15: 11-13
      - 19th century
        Box/Folder 16: 1-2
      - 1856
        Box/Folder 16: 3
      - 1871 (Reel 19)
        Box/Folder 16: 4
      - 1875
        - General
          Box/Folder 16: 5-7
        - "L'Entente des Trois Empereurs"
          Box/Folder 16: 8
      - 1881-1890, "Konets Soiuza Imperatorov"
        Box/Folder 16: 9
      - 1885
        Box/Folder 16: 10
      - 1885-1887 (Reel 20)
        Box/Folder 17: 1
      - 1894-1898
        Box/Folder 17: 2
    - Foreign relations
      - General
        - 1904-1906
          Box/Folder 17: 3
        - 1906
          Box/Folder 17: 4
      - Austria
        - 1801-1841
          Box/Folder 17: 5
        - 1854-1856
          Box/Folder 17: 6
        - 1905-1908
          Box/Folder 17: 7
      - Bulgaria, 1886 (Reel 21)
        Box/Folder 17: 8-9
      - Far East
        - 1860-1862
          Box/Folder 17: 10
        - 1869-1873
          Box/Folder 18: 1
      - France
        - 1856-1858
          Box/Folder 18: 2
        - 1859 (Reel 22)
          Box/Folder 18: 3-4
        - 1887
          Box/Folder 18: 5
        - 1891>
          Box/Folder 18: 6
      - Germany
        - 1852-1853>
          Box/Folder 18: 7
        - 1889-1891
          Box/Folder 18: 8
      - Great Britain, 1853-1954
        Box/Folder 18: 9
      - Poland
        - 1797-1798
          Box/Folder 18: 10
        - 1909 (Reel 23)
          Box/Folder 18: 11
      - United States
        - 1820-1850
          Box/Folder 18: 12
        - 1856-1862
          Box/Folder 19: 1
        - 1862-1865
          Box/Folder 19: 2
        - 1905
          Box/Folder 19: 3
        - 1916
          Box/Folder 19: 4-6
        - 1916 (Reel 24)
          Box/Folder 19: 7
    - Gosudarstvennyi Sovet, 1861
      Box/Folder 19: 8
    - History - Nicholas II, 1894-1917
      Box/Folder 19: 9. Diaires of unnamed individuals
    - Nobility, 19th century
      Box/Folder 19: 10
    - Nobility, 19th century
      Box/Folder 20: 1-2
  - Russia and the West
    - 15th and 16th centuries (Reel 25)
      Box/Folder 20: 3
    - Snegirev, V. L., "Iz Istorii Krest'ianskogo Dvizheniia pri Pavle I,", undated
      Box/Folder 20: 4
  - Russian Naval Archives
    - General
      Box/Folder 20: 5
    - Diary of a Russian Naval officer, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 20: 5A
    - Vasil'ev, Vice Admiral M. N. - Trip around the world, 1819-1822
      Box/Folder 20: 6
  - Russian Naval Fleet, 1905
    Box/Folder 20: 7
  - Russians in Alaska
    - General
      Box/Folder 20: 8
    - Russian-American Company, 1857-1867
      Box/Folder 20: 9
  - Russians in California
    - General
      Box/Folder 20: 10
    - Fort Ross
      Box/Folder 20: 11
  - Russians in Hawaii, 1803-1817
    Box/Folder 20: 12
  - Soviet Union
    - Education (Reel 26)
      Box/Folder 21: 1
    - History - Revolution, 1917-1921
      - General
        Box/Folder 21: 2
      - Anti-Bolshevik propaganda
        Box/Folder 21: 3
      - Diary of G. A. Knizev (in Russian), entitled "Iz zapisnoi knizhki russkogo intelligenta"
        - 1917
          Box/Folder 21: 4
        - 1917-1920
          Box/Folder 21: 5
        - 1918
          Box/Folder 21: 6-7
        - 1919-1921 (Reel 27)
          Box/Folder 21: 8
  - United States - History
    - Revolution, 1775-1783
      Box/Folder 21: 9-10
    - Civil War, 1861-1865
      - General
        Box/Folder 22: 1-2
      - Russian Fleet, 1864-1865
        Box/Folder 22: 3
- American Relief Administration, 1919-1929
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, essays, notes, and printed matter, relating to the operations of the American Relief Adminstration in Europe, the Near East and Russia. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - A.R.A. Association Review, Vol. 4, No. 1, 1929 February (Reel 28)
      Box/Folder 22: 4. Printed copy
    - Shipments of historical materials to Stanford University, 1920-1923
      Box/Folder 22: 5. Correspondence, lists
  - Constantinople Unit, 1922
    Box/Folder 22: 6
  - European Operations
    - Ehrenburg, G., letter and reports requesting aid for Russian refugees in Finland, 1920
      Box/Folder 22: 7
    - European Children's Fund
      - General, 1919-1920
        Box/Folder 22: 8
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1921
          Box/Folder 22: 9
        - Société du Croissant Rouge Ottoman, 1921
          Box/Folder 22: 10
    - Neunkirchen, Austria. Commemorative album of thanks
      Box/Folder 22: 11
    - Ruhr food situation
      Box/Folder 22: 12
    - Accounting and financial records
      Box/Folder 22: 13
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1921-1923
        Box/Folder 22: 14
      - Adams, Ephraim D., 1920-1923